Nayif Alsaheouny.

Iraq, Erbil.

Mobile: +9647508443021.

Email: <u>nayif.alsaheouny@gmail.com</u>.



Professional Profile

Ambitious and hardworking. Specialization in Mechatronic Engineering, open-minded, organized, innovative with good communication and leadership skills, responsive under pressure. A sound understanding of requirements using organisation and planning skills to deliver assignments promptly with a high standard of quality.

Education and Qualifications

Master Professional Master of Technology Management at Syrian Virtual University

(Feb/2018- Present).

Postgraduate Diploma: Solar Energy at Al Baath University (Feb/2016- Present).

BSc: Mechanical Engineering, department of Mechatronic Engineering (Al Baath University)

October 2015.

Course content: (Industrial Automation, Programming PLCs, Artificial Intelligence, Fundamentals in Robots, Control Systems, computer network, Digital Image Processing, Industrial Communications, Mechanical Engineering, Electrical Engineering, Computer Engineering, Information Measuring systems, Maintenance and industrial safety,

Heating ventilation and air conditioning).

Graduate Project: Designing a Ceramic Dental Oven.

Experience

Oct/2016-Jan2018

Consultant, Aga Khan Foundation, Infrastructure Program, Salamieh.

- Study schematic designs and shop drawings of Mechanical and electrical outlines of Salamieh RO project, provide technical feedback, recommendation and modifications to the Infrastructure Programme Manager.
- Oversee the implementation during the installation and electrical connections stages in accordance with and specifications of the project plan.
- Ensure high level of quality control, test the materials and adhere to the work standards of the project related to the installation. Monitoring and control of the facility through the SCADA system.
- Work closely with consultants and other supervisory committees as required.
- Coordinating with the Management Officer.

Feb/2016-Aug/2016 Tutorial assistant, Faculty of Agriculture, Hama University, Salamieh.

Conducting lectures for second and fourth year students

(Renewable energy, Mechanics).

Aug/2014- March2019 Electronic maintenance technician, Salamieh.

Made transformers and electronic electric circuits

Aug/2014-Jan/2016 Central Heating and Air Conditioning maintenance technician, Salamieh.

Voluntary Experience

Mar/2016-Oct/2016

Volunteer, Aga Khan Foundation, WASH Project, Salamieh.

- Participated in hygiene promotion campaigns, design and planning activities.
- Participated in children awareness sessions requiring the optimal use of water and preventative methods of water-borne diseases.
- Participated in social initiatives to raise awareness of disinfection processes and sterilizing of water.
- Participated in distribution hygiene.

March2014-Nov2015

Assistant Manager, Aga Khan for Education services.

Coordinated with the program manager and youth. This was designed for young students to prepare CVs, letters of application, correspondence with universities and small enterprises

Professional Training

Sept 2017 SCADA and PLC course, organized by Aqua Damas Company, Salamieh.

Using PLC and SCADA system (WINCC + STEP 7) for water treatment control

(Reverse Osmosis).

May 2017 Training of Trainers Course (TOT) organized by the Syrian Scientific Society

For Quality (SSSQ), Salamieh.

Oct 2016 Quality Management awareness course, organized by the Syrian Scientific Society

For Quality (SSSQ), Salamieh.

Learning basics in Quality Management (ISO9000)

Nov 2015. Accounting course, Salamieh.

Learning basics in Accounting and Bookkeeping up to Balance sheet and audit process.

Aug2015 Workshops on Debating and Public Relationships, organized by the Junior

Chamber International (JCI) Hama, Syria.

Mar 2015. Training of Trainers Course (TOT) for Heating ventilation and air conditioning

Maintenance course from European Institute of Cooperation and Development

(IECD) Damascus, Syria.

Nov 2014. Microcontrollers Programming, Homs, Syria.

Learning about Microcontrollers Programming using Codevision AVR program.

Languages

- Arabic: Native language.
- English: Fluency in (Reading, Writing,
- Listening, Speaking).
- Kurdish: Beginner.
- Russian: Beginner.

I.T. Skills

- Siemens Step7
- Siemens WinCC
- Solidworks
- MATLAB.
- > AutoCAD Electrical.
- MS Office.